Guide to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Photograph Collection ALBA.PHOTO.015
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Photographs
1927-2000
ALBA.PHOTO.015
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
9.75 linear feet (11 boxes)
The organization Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) was begun informally in 1937 and officially in 1939 by U.S. volunteers returning from the Spanish Civil War. The VALB Photograph Collection contains photographic prints, slides and negatives collected by VALB, donated to the organization over the years, and occasionally used in their New York City offices for publicity purposes, exhibits, etc. The collection is comprised mostly of images of American volunteers in Spain during the Spanish Civil War, including portraits, group shots, and battlefield scenes; it also includes images of demonstrations, support activities, and commemorative events in the United States. There are some photographs of volunteers of other nationalities, of supporters and relatives of the U.S. volunteers, and of prominent individuals such as Paul Robeson and Franklin Delano Roosevelt, as well as images documenting the volunteers' activities in more recent years, including Lincoln Brigade veterans' trips to Spain, Nicaragua, the People's Republic of China, and East Germany.
Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade.
Provenance
The VALB Photograph Collection was donated to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives by VALB in the early 1990s. Additional images came to VALB and were passed on to the Archives in later years. The core collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
U.S. men and women who had volunteered for service in the Spanish Civil War joined together as the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) in December 1937 upon their return from Spain. The organization adopted a constitution and a formal structure in 1939. VALB originally assisted wounded veterans and sought to awaken the U.S. public to the significance of the Spanish Civil War and the Loyalist cause. In later years, VALB campaigned strenuously against the Franco regime in Spain and addressed other political issues, including U.S. policy in World War II and later, in Cuba, Nicaragua, and Vietnam. In addition to their headquarters in New York City, VALB "posts" developed in various cities, including Los Angeles, San Francisco, and Chicago. VALB also created a journal/newsletter, The Volunteer for Liberty (later, The Volunteer). For additional information on the history of VALB see the guide to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Records, ALBA #19.
Scope and Content Note
The Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Photograph Collection was compiled from photographs, slides, and negatives produced by, gathered by, or donated to VALB over the course of its history. Some of the images were donated by veterans and their families or acquired from individuals engaged in filmmaking, journalism, research or publication projects. For the most part, caption information has been taken from notations on the photographs, with minimal editing.
Series I: Photographic Prints. This series contains ca. 2,000 photographs collected by VALB and used in its New York City offices. The series consists mainly of images of American volunteers in the Spanish Civil War, and includes portraits, group shots, combat scenes, and images of demonstrations and support activities in the United States after the Spanish Civil War including protests against the Vietnam War. Dates are provided or estimated when possible. Series I is divided into four subseries, Subseries A: Individuals, is comprised of photographs of portraits and groups in which each individual is identified; Subseries B: Individuals in Groups, includes photographs of larger groups of people in which only one or a few are identified; Subseries C: Subjects, General, includes photographs taken at particular sites as well as images grouped by topic. Subject designations for the most part match those used in the original photo captions; Subseries D: Monuments, Memorials, Celebrations, and Reunion, includes photographs of memorial gatherings, commemorations, reunions and other veterans' events, as well as demonstrations and other political activities in which veterans and their supporters participated. Also included in this series are a few photographs of political notables and other subjects of general political interest.
Series II: Negatives, consist of 204 negative images of U.S. volunteers in the Spanish Civil War (including portraits, group shots, and combat scenes) and of support activities in the United States. All of the negatives have matching prints in the collection; the negative sleeves are marked with the item number of the corresponding print. (Negative numbers are also noted on sleeves or folders of their matching prints.)
Series III: Slides. The 8 slides in this series are images of a 1974 VALB trip to China.
Series IV: Unprocessed Material, consists of a large number of miscellaneous photographs donated to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, or acquired by them for publications, exhibits, etc. but never integrated into this collection. The exact provenance of most of the photographs is unknown. Many folder titles are general; they include any available donor information.
Arrangement
The photographic prints are identified by four numbers separated by colons. The first number refers to the collection number, the second to the box number, the third to the folder number, and the fourth to the individual print. For example, the first print in this collection is labeled 15:1:1:1. (Some prints in the collection were marked with Photograph numbers apparently assigned by VALB: P1, P2, P3, etc. These original numbers are also indicated on the photo sleeves.)
The files are grouped into four series:
I, Photographic Prints, 1930s-1990s.
II, Negatives, Undated.
III, Slides, 1974.
IV, Unprocessed Material
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Records. (ALBA #19)
Carl Geiser Papers. (ALBA #4)
Steve Nelson Papers. (ALBA #8)
Fifteenth International Brigade Photograph Collection (ALBA Photo #11).
Marc Crawford and Abby London Crawford Photo Collection (ALBA Photo #186).
Albert Harris Photograph Collection (ALBA Photo #49).
International Brigades Archive, Moscow: Selected Images (ALBA Photo #177).
Toby Jensky Photograph Collection (ALBA Photo #55).
Fredericka Martin Photograph Collection (ALBA Photo #1).
James Neugass Photograph Collection (ALBA Photo #12).
Edwin Rolfe Photographic Collection (ALBA Photo #10).
Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archive: Small Photograph Collections (ALBA Photo #36).
Abraham Lincoln Brigade.; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Abraham Lincoln Battalion.; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Brigada Internacional, XV.; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade.; Barcelona (Spain); Belchite (Spain) |x History |x Siege, 1937.; Black-and-white photographs.; Ebro River, Battle of the, Spain, 1938.; Jarama (Spain); Murcia (Spain); Negatives (photographic); Quinto (Spain); Slides (photographs); Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Pictorial works.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Portraits.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x African Americans.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Campaigns.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Children.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, American.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, Jewish.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939.; Teruel, Battle of, Teruel, Spain, 1937-1938.
- Series I: Photographs, 1930s-1990s.
  - Subseries I:A: Individuals
    - Aalto, William, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ades, Bernard, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Allander, William, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Altman, David, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Alto, Oscar, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Amlie, Hans (standing portrait); (headshot in uniform); (headshot), undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Amsbury, Clifton, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Archer, Amos, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Arvola, Frank, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bajza, Stephen, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Baker, John (Levie Kaminsky), undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Baran, Joseph, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bard, Philip, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Barr, Charles (seated portrait); (candid, full body, after loss of eye); (2 headshots), undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Barrett, Jack (fox hole, Lincoln-Washington Battalion, Company 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Barsky, Edward K. (on board ship, Jan 1937); (headshot); ("Lift the Embargo" Conference, Washington, DC, Jan 9, 1939), undated, 1937, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bartz, Louis, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bates, Ralph (full body); (seated), undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bauers, Max, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Begelman, Elias, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bellows, Carl, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Benet, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Benet, William Rose, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Berkowitz, Norman Nathan (Spain, thumbnail portrait), undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bessie, Alvah (standing in front of aircraft); (Jun 1953); (Mar 1979), undated, 1953, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bethune, Dr. Norman, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bevensee, Court, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Binn, Max (Mac), undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Birnbaum, Saul (undated); (Sep 20, 1947), undated, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bjoze, Jack (headshot); (receiving Medical Treatment), undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Boise, William, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Borisuk, Paul, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Bottcher, Herman (portrait); (headstone), undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Bourne, James Kenneth, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Bown, Vernon, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Boxer, Harry Jack, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Bradley, Carl (speaking, Brooklyn, Mar 1938) (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Browder, Bill (Teruel, 2 photos, one with Captain Carni), undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Brown, Archie (Nicaragua, VALB trip, 1989) (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Burns, Paul, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Buttonshaw, Joy and Harvey (Feb 15, 1989) (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Callado, Thomas, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Carrol, George, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Carroll, Will, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Cason, Ray, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Chang, Chi (Paris, Oct 10, 1938), undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Cloke, Richard, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Coad, Mack, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Cobbs, Walter, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Coffee, Congressman John M., undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Cohen, Milton, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Cole, Bob, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Cone, Franklin, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Connolly, Eugene (speaking at VALB 5th National Convention, Sep 1946), 1947 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Cookson, John Wilhelm (grave stone and ceremony at monument, Corbera de Ebro, Nov 14, 2000, 2 photos) (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Coopman, Arthur, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Cox, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Cresswell, Virgil Ray, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Cummins, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Curtis, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Davidson, Joe [David?] and two unidentified men, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Detro, Philip Louis Leighton (alone); (with woman, in Spain), undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Dicks, Walter, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Doran, Dave ("International Brigade Commanders Watch Artillery Bombardment," [1938]), undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Drill, Joe, undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Dubac, Constantino, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Dukes, Larry, undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Duncan, Lowell Oswalt and wife, Faiga (Fran) Duncan (1945), undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Edmonds, Lloyd (with Harry Hakam, Feb 1989, Australia); (with Joy and Harvey Buttonshaw, Feb 15, 1989); (with unidentified man [1989]), undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Ehrenberg, Isadore (Podium, 2 photos), undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Ehrlich, Rueben, undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Eider, Louis, undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Engels, David (Engelson) ("Political Commissar First Co. Lincolns," Madrid, 1937), undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Ensign, Joseph, undated (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Escribas, Antonio (Lincoln-Washington Battalion, Company 3, [Spain]), undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Estella, Miguel A., undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Faber, William, undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Fahy, Jack, undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Fajans, Irving (in uniform), undated (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Fast, Howard (speaking at podium, at VALB 54th Anniversary Dinner, New York, 1991), undated (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Feinberg, Phil (collecting donations with cigar, monkey and puppy), undated (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Fernandez, Ramon Via, undated (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Ferrero, Frank, undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Findley, Benjamin Franklin, undated (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Fishelson, Nelson (with unidentified man, on deck), undated (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Fishman, Morris (2 photos), undated (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Fishman, Moses (Moe) (ca. 1930s); (speaking at dedication of the Fredericka Martin Papers, Brandeis University, Aug 12, 1994); (at VALB Monument Dedication, Madison, WI, Oct 31, 1999), 1930s, 1994, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Flammer, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Forester, Clarence Michael, and Carl Geiser (at VALB Monument Dedication, Madison, WI, Oct 31, 1999) (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Forester, Kenneth, undated (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Franco, Francisco, undated (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Freed (Mrs.) (negative only), undated (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Freeman, Maurice, undated (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Friedman, Maurice, undated (Box 1, Folder 93a)
    - Fuhr, Lini, undated (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Fulginiti, Frank, undated (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Gandall, William (Bill) (U.S. Marine Armed Guard, 1927); (Nicaragua, 1928, 3 photos); (Spain, 1938, 2 photos); (painted portrait, Spain, 1939); (woman and child); (after Spain, 4 photos), 1927-1939 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Garland, Walter, undated (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Gerber, Bernard, undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Gianfortoni, Joseph (Salvatore), undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Gladnick, Robert (National Jewish Monthly clipping), undated (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Goland, Philip P. ("On his way to Spain"), Jun 1937 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Goldring, Benjamin (VALB 53rd Anniversary Dinner, New York, 1991) (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Goldstein, Easey, undated (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Golomb, Ned, undated (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Gonsalez, Valentin (2 photos, 1 autographed), undated (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Grachow, Leo (group photo at Hebrew Orphan Asylum), 1920s (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Graeber, Kenneth, undated (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Greenfield, Herman, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Grigane, Alman F., undated (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - Gross, Nathan H., undated (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - Hakam, Harry (at microphone in front of crowd with nurses and sailors); (with 3 unidentified men), undated (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - Halonen, Oiva (at beer tap), undated (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - Haltz, Wilhelm [aka Holtz] (with patients at Castillejo), undated (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - Harris, Aaron, undated (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - Hartzman, Jacob, undated (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - Harvey, William, undated (Box 1, Folder 116)
    - Havens, Bernard, undated (Box 1, Folder 117)
    - Haydock, Philip, undated (Box 1, Folder 118)
    - Hecht, Joe, undated (Box 1, Folder 119)
    - Hegedus, George, undated (Box 1, Folder 120)
    - Heinrich, Hugo, undated (Box 1, Folder 121)
    - Hellman, Lillian, undated (Box 1, Folder 122)
    - Hendrickson, George (Spanish soldiers); (rifle), undated (Box 1, Folder 123)
    - Henman, Luke (Lincoln-Washington Battalion Observer Chief, Gandesa Front, Spain), undated (Box 1, Folder 124)
    - Hewlitt, Wayland, undated (Box 1, Folder 125)
    - Holliday, Judy (collecting for Spanish Republican Refugees Fund); (New York Committee to Win the Peace Waterfront Rally, Oct 1946, 2 photos) (Box 1, Folder 126)
    - Holtzclaw, Leonard Martin ("Cabo," Lincoln-Washington Battalion, Company 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 127)
    - Hooker, Howard, undated (Box 1, Folder 128)
    - Hourihan, Martin William, undated (Box 1, Folder 129)
    - Howard, Joseph Hyman, undated (Box 1, Folder 130)
    - Howard, Wesley, undated (Box 1, Folder 131)
    - Ibarruri, Dolores (ca. 1936-1937, school, top right); (elderly, at podium); (memorial photo at VALB 53rd Anniversary Dinner, 1990), 1936-1990 (Box 1, Folder 132)
    - Iceland, Benjamin Isaac (Jan 15, 1938); (Mar 28, 1938); (1981) (Box 1, Folder 133)
    - Isaacs, Councilman Stanley (Chairman of Tag Days, donating to Spanish Republican Refugees Fund, photo and press release), undated (Box 1, Folder 134)
    - Ives, Burl (dressed as Santa Claus) and Canada Lee (picketing UN headquarters re: Franco's Spain, Dec 1946) (Box 1, Folder 135)
    - Jackson, Eric, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Jacques, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Jones, David Everett, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Jordan, Dennis David, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Jordan, Frank Benjamin, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Kailin, Clarence (portrait); (VALB Monument Dedication, Madison, WI, Oct 31, 1999, 2 photos) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Kampel, Morris, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Katz, Max, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Kee, Salaria [a.k.a. Salaria Kea, later O'Reilly], undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Keith, Irving, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Keller, Fred Paul, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Kelly, Kirby, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Keszering, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Kirby, Robert, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Kisch, Bedrich (Bernie), undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Klein, Rose Harvan (Meyer Levin's wife), undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Klein, Herman [aka Gabby], undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Kleinman, Joseph, undated (Box 2, Folder 17a)
    - Kleinow, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Klonsky, Robert, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Kobeluch, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Kochigian, Harry, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Kohler, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Kohn, Stanley, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Koll, Edwin, Apr 1948 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Kolowski, Walter (left; seated, talking to man with hat), undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Koltsov, Mikhail (Quinto), undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Koslow, Al, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Kozar, John (Feb 1937); (Dec 1, 1938); (Jan 16, 1939); (Canadian Merchant Marine, Mar 4, 1941); (Spain); (Nova Scotia, 1940), 1937-1941 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Kozlowski, Ernest, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Kramer, Jacob A. (portrait); (Belchite), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Krist, Nikolas, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Lamb, Leonard, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Landis, Arthur, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Lane, John Albert [aka Jack], undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Lanser, Manny, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Law, Oliver (Jarama Front, with unidentified soldiers), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Layton, Paul, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Leider, Benjamin (piloting airplane); (reception for his body, New York), Aug 1938 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Lerner, Sol (in Spain), undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Levine, Robert, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Lipton, David Raphael (with group of soldiers, Gandesa), 1938 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Lister Frank (swinging golf club), undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Litsas, Christopher E., undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Loch, Rudolph, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Lord, Frederick Ives (undated); (in uniform), 1943 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Lossowski, Vincent (Panama Canal Zone), 1933 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Love, Vaughn, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Lustgarten, Lawrence (Spain), Nov 1938 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Lutz, Fred G. (Purburell Hill, Spain), undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Malina, Leopold (Austrian volunteer, "1939-1940 Gurs") (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Markert, Clement L., undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Martin, Fredericka (Spain); (Cuernavaca, Mexico 1990); (dedication of the Fredericka Martin Papers, Brandeis University, Aug 12, 1994, includes group photos with Harry Fisher, Moe Fishman, Bill Van Felix, Sam Walters and Fredericka Martin's daughter, Tobyanne Berenberg), 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Martin, Jose ( Life Magazine clipping), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Masterson, Louis, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Matison, Matthew, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - McCarran, Senator Pat (shaking hands with Franco, El Pardo Palace), Nov 1949 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Mendelson, Wilfred, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Merkel, Paul, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Merriman, Robert (in uniform, with soldiers), undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Mills, Saul, undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Miuk, Emanuel ("Last Botwin Brigade [sic] Commander"), undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Muller, John Philip (wife Helen); (Jan 1938); (passport, 1975); (passport, 1977), 1938-1977 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Murphy, Jim [James Patrick or James A.?], 1937 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Negrin, President Juan (standing with other officials), undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Nelson, Robert William, undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Nelson, Steve (in uniform, seated); (VALB 53rd Anniversary Dinner, New York, 1990); (VALB Tribute on 90th Birthday at 54th VALB Anniversary); (VALB Convention, Chicago, 1957), 1957-1990 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Nobel, Harry (at front, standing); (at front with three Yugoslavian soldiers), undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Noble, Marion, undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Nolte, Eugene Victor, undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - North, Joe, undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Norton, Thomas Allen, undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Nowakowski, Anthony, undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Nusser, Charley (Spain), Aug 1937 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Obriat, Jersil, undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - O'Dell, Paul, undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Oderaka, William H., undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - O'Flaherty, Thomas (undated); (Chapel Hill boxing team); (portrait); (standing near palm tree), 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Oliver, Louis, undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Olson, Leonard, undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Osborne, Norman, undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Ozias, Earl, undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Palega, Edward, undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Pangalos, Theodore (5" by 3" print of Greek-captioned photo card); (enlarged copy), undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Panscick, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Pappas, Nick [aka Mike] (id from negative), undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Payne, Melvin Laycock, undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Payne, Perley Baldwin, Jr., undated (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Pena, Leoncio (portrait, studio); (portrait, outdoors); (cropped, WWII), undated (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Penrod, John Arthur, undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Perrone, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Peshkin, Irving, undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Petrovic, Bozidar [aka Bosko] (Yugoslavian aviator, portrait by airplane and brief biographical data, 1937) (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Pike, William W., undated (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Plumb, Franklyn Carroll, undated (Box 2, Folder 94)